We're thrilled uh with with with all
three days questions. You
>> expand on that a little bit cuz a lot of
people thought this was a thin draft,
right? Maybe the last couple rounds
there weren't as many players. You
obviously saw it different. So, what do
you think you got in some of those guys?
>> Yeah, I just look um you know, when when
when you get to day three, I just, you
know, you can throw a lot of the stuff
out the window. You know, what round did
you have him in or what grade did you
have? Look, man, just pick the player
that you want, you know, and so that's
kind of our our mindset. So, I just
thought it was going to be a fun time
just to I don't know if they're going to
be seventh round guys, sixth round guys,
whatever. But, we were able to get some
guys that we had ranked a way higher um
that fell for whatever reason. Um I'm
not really worried about that. We're not
worried about that. We're just thrilled
that we have them. So, that's kind of
how it exceeded my expectations. But all
of them, every single last one of them,
they are complete true fits. Like the
these these guys are lions. Like I know
technically they are, yes, but they they
they fit everything that we're about.
So, um, we got some good football
players.
>> Brad, when you look at the free agency
hall that you had and the draft that you
had, it seemed like everybody that you
got was really good at stopping the run.
Would you say that that's kind of in the
theme of the offseason is making teams
onedimensional? Um well, when you put in
that light, uh yes, I think that comes
along with it, but really you're just
looking for very gritty football
players. And so in order to be able to
do that stuff, you know, in in the run
game, you you do have to have a level of
grit to you. And I know that that was a
huge emphasis uh for um you know, free
agency and the drive process. But uh
that's also the bonus that came along
with it.
instincts last night, right, with with
RER and ABNE. They both seem to kind of
be instinctual players that maybe offer
you some untapped versatility. They
haven't shown at the college level. Um,
when you were scouting them, kind of
what was your initial view of of how
they uh schematically fit defensively?
>> Yeah. Uh, you know, the first time I
looked at Ralder, I was just um I was
like this I just kept seeing football
player. I was like, this guy's a
football player. Thought he was highly
instinctive. Um, again, he was the one
he was the one guy on that Michigan
defense like, you know, like Derek
Moore, like I said, like we've been
watching for a long time and there's
there's other players on that defense or
just on that team period. He was the one
that I hadn't seen in previous years.
And so that was just kind of like a
fresh like, you know, very encouraging
view of him, but he was very
instinctive, was a really good tackler.
Um he doesn't really miss hardly any
tackles and um you know he just plays
with his hair on fire. He's he's
stronger than what you think. He can
actually set edges if you put him on the
edge. But um you know if if you don't
know where you're going and if you don't
have you know high level processing and
instincts it's it can be it can be tough
for you. I don't care how big, strong,
explosive you are as an inside
linebacker. And then Abney was the same
thing. Uh, you know, we've we've
evaluated ABNE, you know, multiple times
throughout this process dating back to
last fall and, uh, every single time,
you know, I always always enjoyed I
think he tilts. He might tilt a little
bit more in the nickel, but, you know,
at this level, but I do think he can
play outside for sure, but he's he's
another instinctive guy that, you know,
he can find the football. Um, he can he
can trigger, he can tackle. Um, he's
he's pretty sticky. I was just he was
just a simple one because we had him
ranked, you know, a couple rounds higher
than where he where he was. So, that was
that was a no-brainer for us.
>> You need to see from an outside corner
to say that that guy will work. We think
that guy will work in the slot.
>> Yeah. Uh yeah, you you really want to
see the instincts and the really the
toughness, you know, you got to do a lot
of things at that nickel spot, you know.
um you got to deal with and you probably
can. Yeah, you want speed to be able to
match vertically, but you want a guy
that has a little bit more short area
suddenness, you know, just to handle the
two-way goes and be able to get off the
spot, but there's a lot of run action
coming at you too at that spot. So, um
you know, um he he he's he's going to be
just fine. But again, um didn't think he
would last that that long. Um and so
just thrilled that we got him.
>> I think the most important thing is that
you accomplished this week. like it
seemed like a meat and potatoes draft,
you know, kind of getting back to the
basics, trenches, and just in your eyes,
what what was sort of the most important
thing you you got done
>> that was that it was just that, you
know, just finding gritty football
players, you know, just kind of, you
know, um getting back to, you know, I'm
not saying that we forgot about our
identity, but you know, um just making
sure that that was at the top of mind.
And so that's why every single player
that we took, like there's sometimes
we're writing notes and I write down,
man, this guy's a football player. and I
go back and I'm reading my notes uh
through all the guys that we picked and
I'm just highlighting that I've said
that about every single one of those
guys. And so um you know as long as me
and Dan are seeing it the same way in
terms of like their football players
that fit us. So um but I would say just
like that was kind of the overall theme
and look that is that is
competitiveness. So, however high that
these guys take it in terms of climbing
the depth chart, um you know, I do think
that um they're going to have the
ability to um potentially makes make
some people uncomfortable.
>> Five of your seven picks were defensive
side. I know you pick the best player
that you like, but was there some
semi-intentional
defensive heavy picks?
>> Uh not not really. Um you know, uh I I
do think I will say this. I think uh the
way that our board was set up that we
had a little bit more volume on the
defensive side and so that's why I think
that it it tilted that way.
>> When you give a player the the football
player label in your notes like in a
given draft, what percentage of players
would you say you you give that label
to? Like how thin is that group of
players that you're choosing from days
one through three?
>> That's a good question. I haven't really
done the math on it. I I would say the
majority of them the majority of them
you know we do or I I I will say along
the way like this guy's a football
player. Um there's really not many guys
that we've drafted. Um you know
especially you're saying rounds one
through four
charges days one through three.
>> Oh days days one one through Yeah. Yeah.
There's not many guys that we don't
think that are you know like football
players how we define football players.
But um but you know, you start getting
into the sixth, seventh round, you know,
um you might, you know, um take a shot
on maybe, you know, some higher traits
or something like that. But um but you
know, I had a lot of conviction about
all these guys this year.
>> You look at Law as somebody to take the
Khif Raymond role.
>> Yeah. Um you know, it's possible. Um you
know, look, so Law,
yes, I I think he can do multiple roles.
Um, you know, there's, you know, I think
the easy lowhanging fruit narrative is
he's the gadget player. Um, what was
very interesting with Law is that for
the first time I saw him, that was 2024
when he was at Alabama and um, me and me
and Ray were at the uh, George Alabama
game and I saw him out there on the
field and I just was impressed about his
build and how explosive he was. I had no
idea who the player was. And so I just
told I was like, "Man, who's that number
one out there?" And so I was calling
Hudith, our college rep. I was like,
"Man, is this guy an underassman? Is he
going to come out and all that?" And
then, um, you know, they said, "No, he's
going to go back to school." And so I
didn't I didn't think about him at all
till, you know, last fall. Um, then he
kind of popped up on the list and I was
like, "Oh, this is a kid that I saw a
year ago at Alabama." And so just kind
of saw. So, I was fired up about just
what he did offensively. I had no idea
about his special teams ability and
that's what really elevated him even
more. Um, and not just a return like
like a Leaf, but this guy can play
Gunner like he can like he's really he's
fourphase special teams player and he's
another one that's just he's he's a dog,
man. He's a football player. You
>> guys obviously filled a lot of holes in
free agency. you're able to come here
and coincidentally fill some some more
holes on the roster. So, how do you feel
just about the player acquisition period
as a whole?
>> Yeah, I mean I I feel good coming out of
this weekend. Uh just because I felt
like um I I do feel like we did do well
in free agency. Uh we put a lot of work
in it. Um and then we felt good about
obviously the the draft. Like I said,
even what we did uh today, it even
exceeded what I thought that we were
going to be able to get. So, yes, I do
feel good, but we're not being
complacent. Um, you guys have heard me
say it all the time, and I'm going to
continue to say it cuz I just think that
that's the mindset you got to have is
that whenever you feel like you're good,
then that's that that's when you can get
your ass whipped. So, um, you just got
to I I I'll always say it it's never
good enough. So, um, uh, we still got
postdraft, you know, um, you know, those
guys are working right now, you know,
for undrafted guys. And you know,
there'll still be some veterans out
there. That'll be very interesting. Um
that we're going to be taking a long
hard look at um next week.
>> You did not draft any
>> uh creating
making people uncomfortable. I mean, is,
you know, is helpful? And and Dan has
mentioned wanting to create more
competition. You mentioned that at the
end of last season. Um how much do you
feel like I mean, again, that was the
that was the goal this off season was to
was to was to do that and and create
competition within the roster. Yeah,
just cuz I I do think we have some
really good players on our team right
now. I I think we have a lot of really
good players, but the more competition,
it just brings out even better
out of those already good players. And
even some young guys that, you know, um
haven't quite gotten their opportunity
yet, you know, that we expect to to get
opportunities this season. Um it's going
to bring out the best in them as well.
So, I just think that the competition is
just it just brings the best out of
everyone and so, um, that's what we were
really focusing on.
>> You did not draft any safeties. Um, what
does that say maybe about your
confidence in Brian Branch and Kirby
Joseph for our health for the for the
year?
>> Yeah, I mean, um, it it wasn't about
like it wasn't that um, we intentionally
didn't draft a safety because we feel
good about them. like I feel like
they're both trending in the right
direction, but um it just it just didn't
line up, you know, just like just like
hasn't hasn't lined up at other
positions in the past. We we didn't
ignore it. Um you know, uh there were
there were some good ones that were out
there that just got picked, you know,
before we were able to, but um it just
didn't it just didn't quite line up. And
I didn't
I didn't really think that class was as
deep either. So, um, you know, you it
had to line up and you had to strike,
right?
>> Just on Branch and and Joseph, I mean,
they got guys in the building this week.
So, do you feel pretty good about maybe
where you thought they'd be?
>> Yeah, like I said, I think they're both
heading in the right direction. Yep.
>> Been a push for some efficiency on some
processes this uh offseason, you know,
with uh skipping the league meetings and
also the removal of the local proday.
Um, rookie mini camp canceled this year.
And so I'm just curious your thought
perspective on the value of that and
where do you maybe supplement some of
the stuff you do there with getting
those guys acclimated?
>> Yeah. Um you know look that's part of
the um I told you guys at the end of the
season me and Dan were going to take a
long hard look at every single thing
from top to bottom and that's what we
did. And so those kind of evolvements
and um or efficiencies that's that that
that was that came about from that you
know um you know not not doing things
just to do it just because you know you
feel like you have to do it you know um
you can't be scared when you want to try
something new that you think is going to
be better for the football team. And so
um so that's what that that's that's
what we did and that's why um some
things are from a calendar standpoint
looks like they're removed but there's
other things are going to be taking
place that I feel is going to be more
beneficial for us
>> supplementing it with like is there you
know is there anything that you can say
that you know how will it benefit the
team I guess you know
>> there's I just can't say it but uh but
yeah but that's um you know we're not
just removing it and just using that as
idle time to twiddle our thumbs that's
it's something that we're utilizing to
put in place of that that's going we
feel that's going to be more efficient
and better for us.
>> Was your draft distinctive this year
from the other drafts? If so, in which
in what way? Either the type of players
you got or the amount you got. What made
it different in your mind, if it is
different than the previous?
>> Um, that's actually a really good
question. Um, look, I take every draft
serious. Um, I just feel like, you know,
it's that's just it's it's too critical
and too important. But I will say um it
was probably a little bit more fire, you
know. Um like you said, like um I know
people like you guys know about me not
going to the meetings, you know, just to
kind of work on some some other things
to make sure that this like it was stuff
like that, but when you miss the
playoffs, you know, um you know, that
that might be some of the that might be
the kick in the rear that you that you
need at times. And so, um, that that
right there, you know, I had it written
up on my office wall and all that kind
of stuff, but, um, yeah, it was just
like not saying I'm I don't have fire in
other drafts or I did not, but you know,
it was just a little bit more, you know,
um, I think every the urgency needed to
be pushed up on on on everything. And
so, um, it was just a little bit more
fire on the, uh, intensity heading into
this one.
>> What did you have written in on your
office wall? What was up there? not not
making the playoffs. I had some other
things I'm not going to say, but it was
just a reminder of that, you know, we
were when those playoffs started, we're
we're sitting at home watching. How
>> does that fire manifest itself? You
know, how did you outside of just like
spending more time on it, how did that
manifest in yourself out of the
>> Yeah, it's just, you know, t taking that
long hard look in the mirror and just
looking at everything from top to bottom
and saying, "Look, like what can we do
to do things better?" You know, what
what what kind of tweaks and changes,
adjustments? And those are the kind of
things that I was talking about at the
end of the season when I said um some of
these adjustments might not come with
the headline. So I wasn't saying that it
wasn't like we're not going to sign a
player or a draft. Like it wasn't about
that. It was just that there's going to
be a lot of things that are going to be
done and tweaked and adjusted that just
might just be internal that might not be
a headline. So um you guys are you guys
are good at your job so you guys you
know kind of get them. So, you guys got
some already, but um but yeah, it was it
was just those kind of things. But I I I
feel a lot better um that we made those
moves and made those adjustments.
>> Specifically, did it say we missed the
playoffs or what what did the word say
on the board that you wrote?
>> Oh, that we did not
>> that you
>> Yeah, I mean, I'm not going to tell you
the specifics, but it was along those
lines. Yeah.
>> A couple more uh defensive trench
players today. Just what do you like in
in West and Gil Howard?
>> Yeah, both of them. um really the um
their their ability to apply pressure as
um as as sub rushers. Um you know, Gil
Howard obviously um you know came from,
you know, Northern Illinois and when he
came here, but he showed pretty
consistent tape in terms of his motor.
He's 100 miles per hour. Uh he's not the
biggest guy, but he's quickness, he's
relentless, he's instinctive, and he can
win quick. Uh so that was that was
intriguing about him. And then the same
way with Tyreek West. uh Tyler West,
there was a he was kind of part of a
rotation with a lot of defensive linemen
that were NFL caliber players. So, um it
wasn't really a knock that he wasn't
like, you know, getting all the snaps.
It just they had they had a lot of guys,
but when he would come in, he would take
advantage of the ops that he got in
terms of being able to apply pressure
and get to the quarterback. So, he was
one we had we we brought him in for a
visit. Um enjoyed the time that we spent
with him and uh felt really good about
him. talked about reestablishing that
grit, you know what I mean? But how
difficult when you guys have success and
the levels you guys reach, you know, to
some extent is it to keep that as the
the players change and everything. How
what have you learned about just keeping
that? How do you how do you guys
maintain that?
>> Yeah, I mean, look, um I you said it,
Eric, it's it's the the the further you
go or the higher you go, um you know, it
takes a little bit extra um urgency and
discipline to make sure that you're
keeping that instilled. Um, you know, I
think everybody's a human being and
everybody can, you know, feel like,
okay, well, what we're doing is working,
so let's keep doing that. And then you
get hit in the face and it's like, whoa,
maybe maybe it's not good enough. And
so, um, those are the things that, you
know, so that was kind of the silver
lining. as much as it sucked to to um to
end the season how it ended, you know,
um you know, that it might have been
what what we needed, you know, and so um
but I'm I'm I'm I'm glad that we um took
a long hard look and but it is it's
harder as you go on.
>> There was a fewer drafts and I guess
we're used to seeing you do. Is that uh
product of maybe the phone just wasn't
ringing or just nothing good was coming
in or you everything fell the way you
wanted it to?
>> Fewer draft trades, you're saying? Yeah,
they only had two this year. Usually
there's
>> Oh, in terms of the movement. Yeah. Um
yeah, I
you know, you can always have a plan and
say, you know, well, look, we can sit
and pick or, you know, I think we just
stay patient. Um I felt pretty good for
the most part on day three that we could
um stay patient, but when we got, you
know, into the fifth round and then, you
know, the players that we selected
there, um you know, they're both there,
I was like, well, we were going to get
both of them. So figured that we were
going to have to make a move up there.
um a little bit with uh Derek Moore, you
know, um it was it was close, you know,
um thought that we but you know, just
like I told you guys, you know, when the
pass rush started coming off the board
and just kind of seeing what was up
behind us. So, there were in smaller
incremental moves, but um you just got
to just react to how the board's
falling. Can
>> I just follow up to that? Yeah, I I
think uh one of the big surprises was uh
you never you didn't trade back into the
third, which I'm not saying you had to,
but it's like u uh it felt expected
almost, but is there any reason why you
didn't go back to the third? Was there
just nothing there that you really
thought, hey, we got to get?
>> No, I just um I mean it kind of fell
kind of fell like how we kind of thought
it would. Um and we felt confident, but
you know um but that was kind of my
sense when we made the Tesla trade as
well. Um just kind of seeing how things
have been going for the past couple
years. Um you know I know that that that
number is a popular number um that
numerical figure but uh the way it's
looking I I had no I had no qualms about
not having those third round picks.
>> You have a sense uh seems to be ne
everybody thinks next year's draft will
be really really good. I don't know if
you've uh got that far yet in terms of
knowing what to expect.
>> Yeah, somebody told me that Yeah, some
somebody told me that the um that the
quarterback class is supposed to be
strong. Um but that's the only I mean I
wouldn't be shocked if it's not stronger
than this past year's, but um but that
that's really the only thing that I
know. I don't really know how strong it
is.
>> Fifth year option deadlines next week.
Uh you guys picking off Jack's option?
Yeah, we're still having those
discussions and trying to see what we're
going to do, but um but yeah, we're
we're having open dialogue, but once we
get them executed, you guys will be the
first one to know.
>> Jack, is there any debate just because
you know, his numbers so high for a
linebacker?
>> Yeah, like I said, it's just we're
having dialogue with you know um you
know the agents and we'll just um you
know when they happen you guys will
know.
>> Brad, is that Rod Wood in your shirt?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. medicine. So,
obviously, uh, Rod's last draft, so, you
know, we wanted to do something special.
We're kind of, we're a little nervous
about how he was going to react, but,
you know, you know, the high school
basketball photo, I thought it was was
pretty cool. So, um, you know, I thought
I thought he handled it pretty well,
actually. You know, I felt like it was
cool, but um, but yeah, I thought it
was, you know, Rod's done so many
special things for everybody else. um
whether it was my jersey last year or
Dan's jersey. I mean, um so it was uh
that was really cool to be able to do
something cool for him because um he he
definitely deserves a lot more than this
cuz um because of all the great things
that he's done for our organization.
>> You guys dig up his high school stats by
any chance?
>> Uh I didn't see the stats. Um but uh but
I just want to make sure that this was
going to pass first. So um yeah, this
passed so we I was kind of good with
that. Yeah. Who got a made this year?
>> What' you say?
>> Did it for you last year, I think.
Right. So, who got him made this year?
We did that.
>> Uh, a he just he kind of just took the
place this year. Yeah. I thought it was
deserving.
>> Thank you, guys.
>> Thanks, guys.